https://www.usrentacar.co.uk/privacy_policy.aspx

Get a quote or call: 0845 226 8523
Loading...
usrentacar.co.uk privacy policy
Data Control
We are U.S. Rent A Car Limited (usrentacar.co.uk) – A company number: 04877174 Registered in the UK. We are the 'data controller' of the information you provide us with, which means we control the way information is used and processed.
How we collect your personal information
When you make a booking online with U.S. Rent A Car.co.uk we require certain information about you and members of your party to complete your request. We need to know your name, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, email address, payment details and in some cases we require the names of each of each person in your party that you have been authorised to provide in order to complete your booking. This information can also be collected when you call us to make a booking.
We will only use your personal information when the law allows us to. We will use your personal information in the following circumstances:
When you consent to us doing so;
Where we need to perform the contract we have entered into with you;
Where we need to comply with a legal obligation;
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Legitimate Interest
Means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience;
We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests;
We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).
We may also use your personal information in the following situations, which are likely to be rare:
Where we need to protect your interests (or someone else's interests);
Where it is needed in the public interest or for official purposes.
Purpose/ activity, type of data and lawful basis for processing
Below is a table description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data.
Some of the above grounds for processing will overlap and there may be several grounds which justify our use of your personal information.
Purpose/Activity
Type of
data
Lawful basis for
processing including basis of legitimate interest
To
register you as a new customer
(a) Identity
(a)
Performance of a contract with you
(b)
Contact
(b)   Your
consent
(c)
Necessary for our legitimate interest to set up and manage your account
and bookings
To process and
deliver your order including:
(a) Identity
(a)
Performance of a contract with you
(a) Manage
payments, fees and charges
(b) Contact
(b)   Necessary
for our legitimate interests (to fulfil your order or recover debts due to
us)
(b) Collect and
recover money owed to us
(c) Financial
(d) Transaction
(e) Marketing and
Communications
To manage our
relationship with you which will include:
(a) Identity
(a) Performance of a
contract with you
(a) Notifying
you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
(b) Contact
(b) Necessary to comply
with a legal obligation
(b) Asking you
to leave a review or take a survey
(c) Profile
(c) Necessary for our
legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how
customers use our products/services)
(c) Responding
to your queries and comments, social media posts and questions.
(d) Marketing and
Communications
(d) Your
consent
To
enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a
survey
(a) Identity
(a) Performance of a
contract with you
(b)
Contact
(b) Necessary for our
legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to
develop them and grow our business)
(c)
Profile
(d)
Usage
(e) Marketing
and Communications
To
administer and protect our business and this website (including
troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support,
reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity
(a) Necessary for our
legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of
administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in
the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring
exercise)
(b)
Contact
(b) Necessary to comply
with a legal obligation
(c)
Technical
To
deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or
understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
(a) Identity
Necessary for
our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our
products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our
marketing strategy)
(b)
Contact
(c)
Profile
(d)
Usage
(e) Marketing
and Communications
(f)
Technical
To use
data analytics gathered from our website, mobile apps to improve our
website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and
experiences
(a) Technical
Necessary for
our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products
and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our
business and to inform our marketing strategy)
(b)
Usage
To
make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that
may be of interest to you
(a) Identity
Necessary for
our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our
business)
(b)
Contact
(c)
Technical
(d)
Usage
(e)
Profile
To
power our security measures and services in order to protect you and our
business
(a)
Identity
Necessary for
our legitimate interest so you can safely access our website and mobile
apps. It also lets us do things such as recognise your username and
password, as well as reset them if you happen to forget what they
are.
(b)
Technical
(c)    Usage
What happens to the data we collect when you make a booking.
We do not pass your data to any other third party. You will only ever receive communication relating to your booking with us or any beneficial offer or promotion.
Promotional offers from us
If you have expressly opted-in to receive marketing from us we may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
Competitions and promotions
From time to time we may run competitions and promotions. You will only receive information on these offers in the event that you have opted in to do so.
How long do we keep your information
By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes. In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information. In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
Site tracking
As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We use tracking software to monitor the visitors to our site and to help us to improve the design and content of the site. This software captures and measures such information as page views and site usage patterns using a cookie system. Cookies are small text files which are sent to your web browser and are stored on the hard drive in your computer. Your browser settings can be set to inform you before receiving a cookie and/or block them.
Third Party or publically available sources.
We may receive personal data about you from third party analytics providers such as Google Analytics based outside the EU, advertising networks and other search information providers.
Disclosure to third parties
usrentacar.co.uk never discloses personal information about its customers to third parties without prior consent, except in the case of an emergency or if we are legally obliged to do so. we will not sell or rent any personally identifiable information we receive from you. usrentacar.co.uk may provide statistics about our customers, sales and booking patterns and related information to third parties, but these will not contain any personally identifying information.
Your rights in connection with personal information
Under certain circumstances, by law you have the right to:
Request access: To your personal information (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Right to withdraw consent at any time: Where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
Fees for excessive or unreasonable requests
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request for access is unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances.
What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is another appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.
Data Protection Officer
The usrentacar.co.uk Data Protection Officer (DPO) oversees compliance with this privacy notice. If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice or how we handle your personal information, please contact the DPO at dpo@usrentacar.co.uk You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO)
Your consent
By using this web site you consent to the collection, storage and use of this information by usrentacar.co.uk as set out in our privacy policy. In the event that we change our privacy policy, we will post any changes on this page, so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. Please note that the information you provide for your booking will be transferred outside the European economic area. By submitting your order, your consent to this transfer.
We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time, and we will provide you with a new Privacy Policy when we make any substantial updates.
